Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, July 24, 1785; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Forster, J[ohann] R[einhold], 1729-1798.
    Halle en Saxe, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces his son, Charles. Has translated Fabroni's work on agriculture. Seeds Son, George, is in Poland. Wants publications on travels. Refers to Heyne and Fontana.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 18, 1787; B F113; 8-3/4x7-1/4; Forster, J[ohann] R[einhold], 1729-1798.
    Halle en Saxe, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning publication on botany by Junghans. Agriculture. Praises Frederick II and his wisdom.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Aug. 26, 1789; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Forster, J[ohann] R[einhold], 1729-1798.
    Halle en Saxe, A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the botanical publication of Junghans. Introduces a travelling companion of the Prince of Brunswick. Asks for help in location Italian publications. Asks for seeds from the Apennines.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Jan. 27, 1786; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Forster, Jean Renaud [Johann Reinhold], 1729-1798.
    Halle and Saxe, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Congratulations on his marriage. Asks for help on chemistry and metallurgy. Botany. Junghans and his method of printing botanical specimens and asks for help in making these publications a success.
  - Concerning Fabroni, B F113; 7-3/4x6-1/2; Fortis,
    basing knowledge on statements by Laplace, etc. D.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 16, 1802; B F113; 9-1/4x7; Fourcroy, [Antoine François de], 1755-1809.
    Paris, 29 fruitidor an 10 A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks him to show prince Dolgoroucki, a Russian prince, through Florence.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Sept. 9, 1806; B F113; 9-1/2x7; Fourcroy, [Antoine François de], 1755-1809.
    Paris, D.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for his zeal.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Paris, June 6, 1803; B F113; 9-1/2x7; François (de Neufchâteau), [Nicolas], 1750-1828.
    Perreaux, 17 Prairial an 11 L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers) Is out of town for the summer. Hopes he can visit. Agricultural news. Refers to Duhamel du Monceau and Alexandre Valléé.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 6, 1793; B F113; Frank, [Luigi Gian Pietro], 1745-1821.
    Pavia, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Praises his work on anatomy.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Aug. 23, [1801]; B F113; 8x6; Fréirille, von
    5 Fructidor an 9 A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces a friend who, he thinks, will be an agreeable companion to Fabroni.
  - Letter to Leopoldo Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 30, 1831; B F113; 10x8; Gallesio, [Giorgio
    A.L.S. 2p.,add.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning grapes and wines.
  - Letter to Leopoldo Fabroni Pelli, Florence, Nov. 30, 1831; B F113; 10x7-3/4; Gallesio, [Giorgio
    Fiosole, A.L.S. 4p.,and.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning grapes and wine.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, 1816; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Gallesio, [Giorgio]
    Florence, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning agriculture.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, March 23, 1816; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Gallesio, Giorgio
    Pisa, A.L.S. 4p.,add.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) His publication. Botany.
  - Letter to Leopoldo Fabroni Pelli [sic], Florence, Sept. 16, 1832; B F113; 8x5 and 12-1/2x8-1/2; Gallesio, Giorgio
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.with 1p.list of grapes and calling card. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning grapes and wine.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Feb. 15, 1816; B F113; 10x7-1/4; Gallesio, Giorgio, conte
    Pisa, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers. Has sent him apple tree. Botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Jan. 1, 1816; B F113; 10x7-3/4; Gallesio, Giorgio, conte,
    Pisa, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Personal difficulties. Concerning work on apple trees, etc. Botany.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 29, 1790; B F113; 9x7; Gallini, Stefano, 1756-1836.
    Padua, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces a fellow scientist.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 29, 1792; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Gallini, Stefano, 1756-1836.
    Padua, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a young doctor.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Sept. 5, 1792; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Gallini, Stefano, 1756-1836.
    Padua, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Presents his publication.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Nov. 23, 1792; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Gallini, Stefano, 1756-1836.
    Padua, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his book. Scientific subjects.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, June 20, 1797; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Gallini, Stefano, 1756-1836.
    Padua, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces a friend.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, April 1, 1800; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Gallini, Stefano, 1756-1836.
    Pisa, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning publications of various persons.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, April 25, 1800; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Gallini, Stefano, 1756-1836.
    Pisa, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Publications.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, [Jan. 1?], 1803; B F113; 10x7-1/4; Gallini, Stefano, 1756-1836.
    Milano, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Changes occuring in Italy. Physics.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni,Florence, Dec. 9, 1815; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Gallini, Stefano, 1756-1836.
    Padua, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning mutual scientific friends and problems. Wishes they could talk.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, B F113; 7x4-1/2; Gatteaux, Madame
    Saturday. A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Oct. 5, 1818; B F113; 10-1/4x8-1/2; Graham, [Sir] G[eorge] F[arquhar], 1789-1867.
    Florence, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his hopes of marrying.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, Feb. 2, 1819; B F113; 10x8-1/2; Graham, [Sir] G[eorge] F[arquhar], 1789-1867.
    Florence A.L.S. 4p. (see Fabroni papers.) Angry letter, explaining his difficulties with Mr. Ferrati and his proposed marriage with Ferrati's daughter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, July 25, 1818; B F113; 10x8; Graham, [Sir] Geo[rge] Farquhar, 1789-1867.
    Florence, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the lady he would like to marry [Ferrati].
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni]; Florence, Nov. 17, 1817; B F113; 9-3/4x8-1/4; Graham, Sir G[eorge] F[arquhar], 1789-1867.
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him of his address on the Square and places one of his windows at his disposal for viewing the amusements.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, March 27, 1802; B F113; 10x7-1/4; Gravier, Yves
    Genova, L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards his catalogue and asks his business.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, March 29, 1799; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Gregoire, [Henri], 1750-1831.
    Paris, 9 Germinal An 7 A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Presents his compliments.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Feb. 25, 1801; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Gregoire, [Henri], 1750-1831.
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning attempt to recall him to Paris. Cuvier, Lacepede, etc. signed such a petition.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, Florence, June 15, 1806; B F113; 6-3/4 x4-1/4; Gregoire, [Henri], 1750-1831.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Neergaard.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 19, 1808; B F113; 8x6; Gregoire, [Henri], 1750-1831.
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards publication on agriculture. Concerning other works, espcially on negroes.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, B F113; 8-3/4x7-3/4; Gregoire, [Henri], 1750-1831.
    Paris. A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Suggests a time they get together.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, Florence, Dec. 12, 1800; B F113; 8-1/2x6-3/4; Gregoire, H[enri], 1750-1831.
    Paris, Frimaire 28, an 9 A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Speaks of regard held for him in Paris.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 13, 1805; B F113; 10-1/4x7-1/4; Grimaldi, [Gabriello
    Zucca, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning an appointment.
  - Letter to Jean Fabbroni, Florence, Aug. 1, 1806; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Grimaldi, [Gabriello
    Lucca, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends diploma of society.
  - Letter to Felix Fontana, Florence, June 23, 1783; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Groenewaud, Simon
    Haarlem, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning seeds and shipment of seeds.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, Feb. 18, [1798]; B F113; 9x6-3/4 and 4-1/4x6-3/4; Guyton [de morveau, Louis bernard], 1737-1816.
    6 Pluviose An 7. A.L. in 3rd P. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to assist at the opening of l'ecole polytechnique.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 26, 1807; B F113; 11x8-1/2; Guyton de Morveau, Louis Bernard, 1737-1816.
    Paris. Typed L. 2p. Translation. Incomplete Advertisement. (see Fabroni papers.) Coinage, and how the French government regulates its manufacture.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 5, 1805; B F113; 9x7; H[umboldt, Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S.with initial. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Yellow fever and publication on the epidemic at Leghorn. Concerning Alexander
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 22, 1793; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Harrison, J
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks for name of a good teacher of Italian for his daughter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, June 5, 1794; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Harrison, J
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Presents scientific machine to him.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Dec. 8, [1801]; B F113; 11-3/4x8-1/2; Hastrel,
    Florence, 17 Frimiaire an 10. A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) General Clarke wishes him to show the natural history museum, etc. to some English officers..
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 7, 1806; B F113; 9x7; Hautrive, [Alexandre Maurice Blanc de Lanutte, comte d'], 1754-1830.
    Paris, L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Death of Fontana. Concerning his publications.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Sept. 12, 1807; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Haüy, [René Just], 1743-1822.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Has been busy on his work on mineralogy Chemical experiments. Refers to Mazzei.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Aug. 19, 1793; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Hervey, [Frederick August, 4th earl], 1730-1803.
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks him for publication, forwarded by Banks.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Haymarket, Aug. 15, 1779; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Higgins, B[ryan?, 1737?-1820].
    Soho, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to Mr. Ellison's for dinner, and directions for arriving there.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni] Parma, Feb. 18, 1804; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Hitroff,
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Desires information concerning hospitals, schools, etc. in Tuscany. Forwards publication. Thanks for his hospitality.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Parris, B F113; 8x5; Hitroff,
    Monday morning. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner given by a Russian duke.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, B F113; 9x7-1/4; Holland, Lord
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Hopes he can helf Fabroni When Fabroni needs something in England.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 15, 1785; B F113; 9-1/2x7; Home, James, 1760-1844.
    Milan, A.L.S. 2p. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for his courtesies. Concerning experiment by Priestley and Fontana. Plans for his travels.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], June 24, 1803; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Roeckner and von Jassinski. Letter from Alexander; suggests it publication in an Italian journal.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, June 30, 1803; B F113; 9-1/2x7; Humboldt, [Wilhelm freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni Papers.) Introduces von Buesch.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, July 6, 1803; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces, and praises, Friedrich Rehberg and another German.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 1, 1803; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Promises to write more frequently. Hasmet Prince Dolgorouki. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, July 11, 1803; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Carl Ludwig Fernow.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 14, 1803; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Mineralogy. Thanks for his publication of Alexander's letter. News of Alexander. Lists his own literary work. Study of the Basque language.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Oct. 28, 1803; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Received his work on the ancient settlements of Italy and comments on it. Also received copy of his brother's letter Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 25, 1804; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 7p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Praises Fabroni's work on settlements of Italy and discusses his own theories. Discusses his studies of languages: Latin and Celtic especially. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], June 23, 1804; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks him to help spread the news of a new edition of Homer by Prof. Friedrich Augustus Wolf, of Halle. Refers to Alexander von Humboldt.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 22, 1804; B F113; 9-1/4x7; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Praises Fabroni's new book. Concerning his brother Alexander. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 20, 1804; B F113; 9-1/4x7; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends Alexander's voyage, printed in Philadelphia. Concerning Alexander. Inquires about Tuscan customs for a friend Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Nov. 16, 1804; B F113; 9-1/4x7; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his wife. Epidemic in Livorno and quarantine there. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Nov. 23, 1804; B F113; 9-1/4x7; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Does not believe epidemic in Leghorn to be yellow fever and comments on Rome's handling yellow fever cases.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 7, 1804; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Hopes quarantine will soon be lifted at Leghorn. Speaks of literary production of Fabroni and self, he is translating Agamemnon into German.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 21, 1804; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Languages. Concerning his brother's, Alexander,publications. Balloon trip from Paris to Rome.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 8, 1805; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning epidemic at Lighorn and Fabroni's reports on it.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 15, 1805; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Plans to write on contageous diseases. Concerning his brother, Alexander.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 29, 1805; B F113; 9x7; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) German medical publication on epidemic at Leghorn.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 19, 1805; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni Papers.) Forwards publication on epidemic in Leghorn. Concerning Alexander.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 26, 1805; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Alexander's travel to Rome.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, May 15, 1805; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Refers to Alexander. Concerning Mme. de Stael. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, May 24, 1805; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers). Comments on Fabroni's work. Concerning brother Alexander's translating.his work into German.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, June 10, 1805; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (See Fabroni papers.) Introduces Prof. Spalding.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Aug. 10, 1805; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) He and Alexander have been ill. Earthquakes at Naples.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Oct. 5, 1805; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sorry Alexander did not meet him on his return to Berlin. War in Europe. Praises Fabroni's administration in Tuscany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 9, 1805; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Greek visitors and his interest in Greece. Scientific experiment discussed with Alexander.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Jan. 20, 1808; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Humboldt, [Wilhelm, freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Met Rennenkampf. Alexander in Paris. Asks Fabroni to Review first volume of his voyage. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Nov. 30, 1804; B F113; 9-1/4x7; Humboldt, [Wilhelm,freiherr von], 1767-1835.
    Rome, A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Epidemic at Leghorn declining. Deaths of his children.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 2, 1805; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Humboldt, A[lexander von], 1769-1859.
    Rome, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Galvanism. Chemical experiments and Volta. Anatomy and botany.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, April 26, 1817; B F113; 9-1/4x7; Humboldt, A[lexander von], 1769-1859.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Wach. Enclosed book by self in Latin ready for publication.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 1, 1819; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Humboldt, A[lexander von], 1769-1859.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Dr. Scholz who wishes to use the Library at Florence.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, May 27, 1817; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Humboldt, Alex[ander von], 1769-1859.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Recommends Marquis de Fagoaga, a young Mexican traveller.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 9, 1805; B F113; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Regrets they do not meet, since he did not pass through Florence. Mme de Steal brings publication by him and Gay.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 21, 1820; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.and end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Abraham Constantin.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 27, 1784; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Ingenhousz, [Johannes], 1730-1799.
    Vienna, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Dr. Home and asks that he be introduced to Fontana.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni., B F113; 3-3/4x5; Ingenhousz, [Johannes], 1730-1799.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], B F113; 7-3/4x5-1/2; Junquieres, [Jean Baptiste] de, 1713-1786.
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni., B F113; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Junquieres, [Jean Baptiste] de, 1713-1786.
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for his favor.
  - Letter to Madame Teresa Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 19, 1803; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Kauffmann, Angelica, 1741-1807.
    Rome, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, May 31, 1780; B F113; 9x7; Kirwan, R[ichard], 1735-1812.
    London, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Cannot visit him. Electricity. Chemistry. Concerning Bergman. Refers to Nairne, Priestley and Raspe.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 15, 1786; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Kirwan, R[ichard], 1735-1812.
    London, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Chemistry. Refers to Wedgwood, Banks, Priestley,and Fontana.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, June 2, 1787; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Kirwan, R[ichard], 1735-1812.
    London, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sorry he cannot visit Ireland. Has published on phlogiston against Lavoisier and given a copy to Magellan. Refers to Wedgwood.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], October 1, 1791; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Kirwan, R[ichard], 1735-1812.
    Dublin, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning chemical experiments which are going on. Mineralogy. Refers to Walker, Fontana, Banks, etc.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 16, 1785; B F113; 9-1/2x7; La Blancherie, [Flammès Claude Catherine Pahin Champlain de], 1752-1811.
    Paris, A.L.in 3rd.P. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a contest. Concerning the exchange of publications. This is written on: Inst.de Fr.Acad. de Inscr.& Belles-Lettres...;July 1, 1785. Broadside.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, July 13, 1785; B F113; 5x7-1/2; La Blancherie, [Flammès Claude Catherine Pahin Champlain de], 1752-1811.
    Paris, A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add.: "adjoint à M. l'Abbé Fontana." In French. (see Fontana papers.) Thanks him for publication sent to the Institut de France.